所以半组无处不在，就像，无处不在。
So semi groups are everywhere, like, everywhere.
所以当你定义一个半时你必须考虑的主要事情
And so the main thing you have to kind of think about when you're defining a semi
如果我们让这个运算符像这里的特殊运算符一样，group 会怎样
group is what if we make this operator this kind of like special operator here
我们将用加联合交集、析取来重载它，
and we're going to overload it with plus union intersection, disjunction,
连接和几乎任何运算符。
conjunction and pretty much any operator.
我们可以用同样的方式做 max 和 min，min 大于和小于。
We can do max and min in the same way with min greater than and less than.
所以如果我说一大于三大于七或
So if I said one greater than three greater than seven or
零，无论如何，我们可以关联地做到这一点，并且它已关闭。
zero, whatever, we can do that associatively and it's closed.
所以半群无处不在。
So semigroups are everywhere.
我们将在编程中将它们定义为数据类型。
And we're going to define them in programming as a datatype.
所以让我们做 Sum。
So let's do Sum.
我们将呼叫那个特殊的接线员，我们将有
And we're going to call that special operator, we're just going to have
一个方法，因为我们不想在 JavaScript 中进行运算符重载。
a method because we don't want to do operator overloading in JavaScript.
这是一种痛苦的屁股，提供了技巧之类的价值。
It's a pain in the butt gives like value of tricks and whatnot.
所以我们要继续，就这样做。
So we're going to go ahead and just do it this way.
所以如果我要把一个总和与另一个总和连接起来，
So if I'm gonna concat a sum with another sum,
好吧，让我们从我们要写的内容开始吧
well let's actually start with what we gonna write so
我们会说 5 的 3 个连续和，而我们想要的是 8 的和。
we'll say 3 concat sum of 5, and what we want is the sum eight.
现在这是一件奇怪的事情。
Now that's a weird thing to do.
[笑] 我们要做的是制作一个我们正在编程的接口
[LAUGH] What we're trying to do is make an interface that we're programming to that
捕获了我刚刚与半组讨论的所有示例。
captures all those examples that I was just talking about with the semi groups.
所以我们有这些可以以多种不同方式实现的二元运算符
So we have these binary operators that can be implemented in many different ways and
它们是关联的和封闭的。
they're associative and closed.
我们可以在一个对象上创建一个接口
We can make an interface on an object and
说一个类型，然后说 concat 是那个运算符，对吗？
say around a type and just say concat is that operator, right?
它将左侧的事物与右侧的事物连接起来，并且具有关联性和
It concats the thing on the left with the right and it's associative and
它已关闭，这意味着如果我连接两个总和，我总是会得到一个总和。
it's closed, meaning I will always get a sum out if I concat two sums.
因此，让我们继续执行此操作。
So let's go ahead and implement this.
Sum 我们总是要返回一个和，我们必须在这里公开这个 x。
Sum we're always going to return a sum and we have to expose this x here.
所以我可以从另一个上取下 x。
So I can get the x off the other.
所以我们会说 sum x 加上 other.x，所以每个人都会看到它是如何工作的。
So we'll say sum x plus other.x, so everybody see how that works.
这是一个有点有趣的语法。
That's a it's a bit of an interesting syntax.
你不会经常看到它。
You don't see it very often.
有了这些小工厂函数，我只是，
With these little factory functions, I just,
这是定义这类东西的最简单的方法，我只是坚持使用它。
it's the slimmest way to define this kind of stuff and I just stick with it.
但是有人对此感到困惑吗？
But is anybody getting hung up on this?
好的，所以我们要做的是希望这个
Okay, so we're going to do is hopefully this
会说八的总和，我认为幺半群为零。
will say sum of eight, I think monoids zero.
它并不是真的要说八的总和，但 x 是八，而且它有一个连接。
It's not really going to say sum of eight, but x is eight, and it's got a concat.
这就是我们的总和。
So that's our sum.
我们可以在上面定义一个两个字符串。
We can define a two string on it.
那会很好，但我们不要经历那个。
That would be nice, but let's not go through that.
所以我们可以用产品来做到这一点。
So we can do this with products.
让我们继续用产品来做到这一点。
Let's go ahead and do this with products.
那只是乘法，对吗？
And that would be just multiplication, right?
而不是加号，很酷。
Instead of plus, cool.
因此，让我们将 sum 更改为 product。
So let's change sum to product.
三乘五，我们应该得到产品。
Three times five and we should get the products.
我们走了。
There we go.
哎呀产品。
Oops products.
总和五。
Sum five.
我在这里做了什么？
What did I do here?
我们走了。
There we go.
我们就在那里。
And there we are.
15 我们做点什么吧，
15 how about let's do any,
这是这个或那个的名称。
which is the name for this or that.
所以让我们说 any 是另一个的 x 。
So let's say any is x for the other one.
我可以说任何真正的 concat 任何错误。
I could say any true concat any false.
好的，所以如果这些中的任何一个是真的，我们将得到一个任何真的和
Okay, and so if either of these are true, we'll get an any true and
如果有的话，那么我们就可以跑得那么快。
if either, so we can just run that real quick.
说实话。
Get true.
他们都是假的，我们会得到假的。
They're both false, we'll get false.
这种捕获了遍历数组的想法并
This kind of captures that idea of running through an array and
看看有什么是真的还是假的。
seeing if anything is true or false.
它结合了所有内容，并告诉您答案是真实的还是真实的
It combines everything and tells you the answer of if you had a true or
假，所以我们可以看到我们将看到其中一些在行动。
false, so we can see we're going to see some of these in action.
但我只是想让你感受一下正在发生的事情。
But I just want you to get a feel for what's happening.
我们正在将此操作提升为一种类型
We're lifting this operation into a type so
我们可以编程到名为 concat 的接口。
we can program to the interface called concat.
然后我们可以交换这些类型。
And then we can swap these types out.
但是 concat 的行为方式总是相同的。
But concat always behaves the same way.
也许有趣的最简单的就是字符串。
Perhaps the interesting the simplest one is just strings.
打个招呼 [LAUGH] concat 它已经内置了得到了解释。
Say hi [LAUGH] concat it's already built in got an explanation.
还有砰。
And bam.
我们打个招呼。
We get hi.